[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [0, 2, 5, 4], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [3, 1, 2, 0], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+N\u2081+20=0", "+N\u2081-20=0", "-N\u2081+20=0", "-N\u2081-20=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+N\u2081-20=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and ceiling/ground 1yellow block and ceiling/ground 2", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to c1?", "options": ["N1 perpendicular up", "N1 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 rightwards", "T\u2081 leftwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+N\u2081+20=0", "+N\u2081-20=0", "-N\u2081+20=0", "-N\u2081-20=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: N1, ", "Downward Forces: 20", "Rightward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the x-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081=2a\u2081", "-T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "+T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and ceiling/ground 1yellow block and ceiling/ground 2", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the x-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081=2a\u2081", "-T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: N1, ", "Downward Forces: 20", "Rightward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+N\u2082-30=0", "+N\u2082+30=0", "-N\u2082+30=0", "-N\u2082-30=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "+N\u2082-30=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and ceiling/ground 1yellow block and ceiling/ground 2", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to c2?", "options": ["N2 perpendicular up", "N2 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 leftwards", "T\u2081 rightwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+N\u2082-30=0", "+N\u2082+30=0", "-N\u2082+30=0", "-N\u2082-30=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: N2, ", "Downward Forces: 30", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: T\u2081, "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the x-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081+5=3a\u2082", "+T\u2081-5=3a\u2082", "-T\u2081-5=3a\u2082", "-T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "-T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "N\u2081: Normal between red block and ceiling/ground 1yellow block and ceiling/ground 2", "N\u2081: Normal between "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the x-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081+5=3a\u2082", "+T\u2081-5=3a\u2082", "-T\u2081-5=3a\u2082", "-T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: N2, ", "Downward Forces: 30", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: T\u2081, "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082", "-a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081y: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2081: acceleration of red block in x-direction", "a\u2082y: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2082: acceleration of yellow block in x-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2081 +a\u2082"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "type": "advance"}]}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= -20.0, a\u2082= -1.0, T\u2081= -1.0, N\u2081= -30.0, N\u2082= -2.0", "a\u2081= -1.0, a\u2082= -2.0, T\u2081= -20.0, N\u2081= -30.0, N\u2082= -1.0", "a\u2081= -30.0, a\u2082= -2.0, T\u2081= -1.0, N\u2081= -1.0, N\u2082= -20.0", "a\u2081= 1.0, a\u2082= 1.0, T\u2081= 2.0, N\u2081= 20.0, N\u2082= 30.0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "finalanswer", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "Red block: +N\u2081-20=0", "Red block: +T\u2081=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +N\u2082-30=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+5=3a\u2082", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= 1.0, a\u2082= 1.0, T\u2081= 2.0, N\u2081= 20.0, N\u2082= 30.0"]}]}]